[{"question":"the (masc.)\n\nThe boy runs through the park.","answer":"el\n\nEl niño corre por el parque.","categories":["article"]},{"question":"the (fem.)\n\nThe girl is eating an apple.","answer":"la\n\nLa niña come una manzana.","categories":["article"]},{"question":"and\n\nAnd I ran out.","answer":"y\n\nY yo salí corriendo.","categories":["conjunction"]},{"question":"a, an (masc., fem.)\n\nA boy runs through the park.","answer":"un, una\n\nUn niño corre por el parque.","categories":["adjective"]},{"question":"to be (norm)\n\nI am a teacher.","answer":"ser\n\nsoy, eres, es, somos, sois, son\n\nYo soy un profesor.","categories":["verb"]},{"question":"to have\n\nI have to be careful.","answer":"tener\n\ntienes, tiene, tenemos, tienen\n\nTengo que tener cuidado.","categories":["verb"]},{"question":"man, mankind, husband\n\nThe man walks down the street.","answer":"el hombre, pl. hombres\n\nEl hombre camina por la calle.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"house\n\nThe house is clean.","answer":"la casa, pl. casas\n\nLa casa está limpia.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"woman, wife\n\nThe woman is intelligent.","answer":"la mujer, pl. mujeres\n\nLa mujer es inteligente.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"son, [pl] children\n\nMy son is playing with his friends.","answer":"el hijo, pl. hijos\n\nMi hijo está jugando con sus amigos.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"problem\n\nThe problem is very complicated.","answer":"el problema, pl. problemas\n\nEl problema es muy complicado.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"father\n\nMy father takes me to the park.","answer":"el padre, pl. padres\n\nMi padre me lleva al parque.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"idea\n\nI have an interesting idea.","answer":"la idea, pl. ideas\n\nTengo una idea interesante.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"friend\n\nMy friend and I went for a walk.","answer":"el amigo, pl. amigos\n\nMi amigo y yo salimos a caminar.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"mother\n\nMy mother takes care of me a lot.","answer":"la madre, pl. madres\n\nMi madre me cuida mucho.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"door\n\nThe door is open.","answer":"la puerta, pl. puertas\n\nLa puerta está abierta.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"table, board\n\nThe table is in the kitchen.","answer":"la mesa, pl. mesas\n\nLa mesa está en la cocina.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"animal\n\nAnimals are very fun.","answer":"el animal, pl. animales\n\nLos animales son muy divertidos.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"doctor\n\nThe doctor recommends a healthy diet.","answer":"el médico, pl. médicos\n\nEl médico recomienda una dieta saludable.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"letter, (playing) card\n\nShe writes a letter.","answer":"la carta, pl. cartas\n\nElla escribe una carta.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"plan\n\nThe plan is very interesting.","answer":"el plan, pl. planes\n\nEl plan es muy interesante.","categories":["noun"]},{"question":"daughter\n\nMy daughter is studying for an exam.","answer":"la hija, pl. hijas\n\nMi hija está estudiando para un examen.","categories":["noun"]}]